Tommy Mallis

770-262-0006 / tommymallis@gmail.com / www.linkedin.com/in/tommy-mallis/

Software Developer

Motivated, self-starting software developer with well-rounded experience in MERN stack development. Combining technical, analytical and problem-solving skills with professional experience in software development to build, test and debug websites, apps and platforms thoughtfully for user experience and company growth.

Experience

Software Developer – Alexandria Labs San Diego, CA, 11/2019 – Present

Responsible for design and architecture of Full Stack applications built on top of Open Index Protocol, a Blockchain solution for content distribution and payments. Built web apps with HTML, SASS/CSS and React js, utilizing hooks, Redux and other React features to produce thoughtful state management for a solid front-end experience. Designed back-end solutions using Node, Express and MongoDB/Mongoose. Built web app from scratch with custom REST APIs for user creation, login, authentication, etc. Apps were shown to investors to raise funding for blockchain based application development.

Front-End Developer/Support Engineer – DataFinch Technologies Atlanta, GA, 02/2019 – 11/2019

Front-End responsibilities were design and layout of our technical user guide for our customers. Used HTML, CSS, JS and Bootstrap to implement technical instructions for our user guide web page. Collaborated with UX/UI research team, QA team and Developers to test and resolve bugs or problem areas within our mobile app and web portal discovered when working with clients. Used Zendesk and JIRA for bug tracking and resolution. Ran queries to pull customer data from database using SQL within SQL Server Management Studio.

Technical Support Software Rep - Varian Medical Systems Atlanta, GA, 05/2018 - 02/2019

Provided support for Varian's Radiation Oncology software to over 200 clinics, resolving issues with Varian's proprietary software and servers, tracked issues/tickets with Salesforce. Supported clinical server environments running Varian software and monitored and troubleshot any issues reported. Provided consultative services when asked questions about clinics current systems configuration and what would be needed for upgrades.

NOC Engineer – ServIT Kennesaw, GA, 04/2017 – 05/2018

Sole employee responsible for overnight resolution to IT related issues for our largest contract Southwire Company LLC. Remotely accessed servers and workstations via Solarwinds and RDP. Responsible for user creation via Active Directory and Microsoft Exchange.

Education

Kennesaw State University, 2017 Emphasis in Web Development

B.S in Information Technology, Cum Laude

Technical Skills

github.com/whoop-t

Programming – HTML, CSS, SASS, JavaScript, React, Redux, Node, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, SQL Tools – Scrum, JIRA, Salesforce, Monday, Trello